<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Assessment ID="R8A_1" ProductName="Reading" ProductID="1000" Grade="8" Level="8" Title="Grade_8_Reading_A" Form="A" TimeLimit="45" Version="v1.2_7/31/02" Description=""><SubTest ID="R8A_1" ProductID="1000" ContentArea="Reading" Grade="8" Level="8" Title="Grade_8_Reading_A" Form="A" TimeLimit="45" Version="v1.2_7/31/02" Description=""><ItemSet ID="R8A1_IS1"><Item Sample="" SuppressScore="" FieldTest="" Manipulative="" ID="8R.1.1.1.11" SequenceNo="" Template="4" ObjectiveID="8R.1.1.1"><Hierarchy CurriculumID="8" Type="Grade" Name="Grade 8" Number="1281"><Hierarchy CurriculumID="8R" Type="Content Area" Name="Reading" Number="1767"><Hierarchy CurriculumID="8R.1" Type="Strand" Name="Vocabulary" Number="1768"><Hierarchy CurriculumID="8R.1.1" Type="Standard" Name="Word meaning" Number="1774"><Hierarchy CurriculumID="8R.1.1.1" Type="Benchmark" Name="Context clues" Number="1793"/></Hierarchy></Hierarchy></Hierarchy></Hierarchy><StudentDirections ID="500964">Read the passage. Then answer questions 1 - 7.</StudentDirections><Stimulus ID="GM.Heroic Hearing Dog"><Heading ID="504190"><P ALIGN="CENTER"><B>Heroic Hearing Dog Keeps on Truckin'</B></P><P ALIGN="CENTER">by Martin Snapp</P><BR/></Heading><Passage LengthInWords="" Readability="" Genre="" ID="504188"><P ALIGN="LEFT"><B>She was an abandoned dog with nowhere to go. Now Hearing Dog Mitzi has places to go, people to see, and a job to do.</B></P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">It was love at first sight when James Reeves met his new dog, Mitzi, on their first day of class at the Hearing Dog Program. From that moment on, the hard-of-hearing truck driver and the gentle golden retriever were inseparable.</P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">But just how close they'd become wasn't apparent until a few days later, when they were doing a training exercise. During the lunch break, James and Mitzi walked down to the local convenience store to buy a few groceries. On their way back, James was almost robbed.</P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">But the bad guy didn't count on Mitzi, who instinctively jumped up and grabbed his shirt sleeve, frightening him away.</P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">Of course, Hearing Dogs are not trained to be aggressive. In fact, biting someone is a no-no that usually means automatic disqualification from the program.</P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">And that's what was worrying James when the police arrived. "Oh, no!" he said. "I've got an aggressive dog!"</P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">Fortunately, one of the cops was a former member of the Police Department's K-9 unit, and he was an old hand with dogs. He took Mitzi aside and played with her for a few minutes. Then he came back and said, "Hey, you have nothing to worry about. This is one sweet dog. When she tried to protect you, she was just doing what comes naturally."</P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">James was shaken up, but otherwise he was okay. He and Mitzi graduated from the Hearing Dog Program on schedule, and James celebrated by buying a new 18-wheeler. From day one, Mitzi has ridden right next to him wherever he goes.</P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">"She really likes having a new place to investigate every time she gets out of the truck," says James. "She has made many friends all over the USA. Some places we go to a lot, and they know her by sight. And I don't have to use her Hearing Dog vest to take her in with me--which is good, since the weather can often get really hot."</P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">When he and Mitzi first hit the road, James had one lingering concern: How would the other truck drivers react? It turns out he needn't have worried. "Much to my surprise and joy, 99 percent of them love her," he says. "I get a lot of comments about how they wish they had a dog who was so well-behaved and loyal."</P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">But at one restaurant a waitress refused to let Mitzi in the door. James patiently tried to explain the law to her, but she was having none of it. "I don't care what the law says," she said. "That dog is not coming in here."</P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">Frustrated, James was ready to go somewhere else. But then a driver at the counter stood up and said, "If you don't let that dog in, I'm walking out."</P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">Then another driver stood up. And another. And another and another and another, until every driver in the place was threatening to walk out. Finally, the waitress grudgingly gave up and let Mitzi in.</P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">"I was embarrassed, more than anything else," says James. "I didn't want to cause a scene--I just wanted to get something to eat."</P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">But that incident was a lone exception. At other truck stops Mitzi is so popular, the waitresses trot out a big bowl of water for her as soon as they see her and James walking in the door.</P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">And it's not hard to start a conversation with Mitzi around. "Before I got Mitzi, I usually sat and ate alone," says James. "Now there is usually always someone who wants to visit and talk, because they see Mitzi."</P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">People are amazed when James tells them all the things Mitzi helps him with every day. When he and Mitzi stay at motels, she wakes him when the alarm goes off and tells him when someone knocks on the door. "Or when someone is pounding on the wall because the TV is too loud," says James sheepishly. "I'm not totally deaf, just hard of hearing, and sometimes I turn the sound up too high."</P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">Mitzi even surprised James one day with a trick she taught herself. She was waiting for him in the truck, and when she saw him approaching she reached up and pulled the cord for the air horn. "After that, every time I got out of her sight, she'd hit the air horn," laughs James. "I finally had to break her of it because she was waking people up, but she is sooooo smart! I don't mean to brag so much about her, but I can't help it."</P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">But Mitzi hasn't forgotten that encounter with the mugger. To this day, she always insists on warning James when somebody is approaching from behind. Besides the joyful companionship and invaluable sound-alert services Mitzi provides, her presence comes with a fringe benefit. "We play and exercise every day, so I'm in much better shape than before I got her," says James.</P><BR/><P ALIGN="LEFT">"I love her very much, and I don't even want to think of what I would do without her."</P><BR/></Passage><Acknowledgement><P ALIGN="LEFT">Adaptation of "Heroic Hearing Dog Keeps on Truckin'" by Martin Snapp from <I>Our Animal</I> Magazine's Winter 1998 issue, copyright (c) 1998 by San Francisco SPCA. Used by permission.</P></Acknowledgement><Graphic ID="Mitzi_08rSB"><Flash FileName="image.swf" Position=""/><BMPPrint FileName="Mitzi_08rSB.bmp" Position=""/></Graphic></Stimulus><Stem><P><B>Read the sentence.</B></P><P>From that moment on, the hard-of-hearing truck driver and the gentle golden retriever were <U>inseparable</U>.</P><P><B>Which of these phrases could <U>best</U> substitute for the underlined word in the sentence?</B></P></Stem><SelectedResponse ID="500965" NumberAnswerChoices="4"><AnswerChoice ID="500966" Type="Distractor">full of</AnswerChoice><AnswerChoice ID="500967" Type="Correct">never apart</AnswerChoice><AnswerChoice ID="500968" Type="Distractor">not accepted</AnswerChoice><AnswerChoice ID="500969" Type="Distractor">difficult to find</AnswerChoice></SelectedResponse></Item></ItemSet></SubTest></Assessment>